(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-07-27T00:26:19.526971",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
クワックイリだよ
Kwakkui is here!
せーの！ こよだよ！
Ready, set! It's Koyori!
はっちだぐ こより実験チュウだし！
Hatchibug Koyori is experimenting right now!
オーケー こよは スマホレスのアー
Okay, Koyori is smartphone-less, ah...
いやだ！
No way!
こよりスケッチしてる！ はい！ はい！
Koyori is sketching! Yes! Yes!
研究室らしーい！ 新型！
Typical of a lab! A new model!
見逃しの新参！
A newcomer who missed it!
こよりの宿直は寝る！
Koyori's night shift is sleeping!
ヘルプ！
Help!
オールナイトニッポン！
All Night Nippon!
すももなんてね！ 見栄っ張り！
Plums or whatever! Show-off!
おもいいでスクウェア！
Memory Square!
オーケー！ こよだよ！
Okay! It's Koyori!
実況者！ 間に合った！
Commentator! Made it in time!
マヨネーズは飲み物です！
Mayonnaise is a drink!
鼻にフガチを吸う気で！
Breathing in fugachi through the nose!
お肉！ 全開！
Meat! Full throttle!
冷凍うどんわ常備してます？
Do you always keep frozen udon stocked?
どうですか？ はい！ やったー！
How is it? Yes! Yay!
証明完了！ QD！
Proof complete! QD!
コックだろコック！ にゃ！
You're a cook, right, a cook! Meow!
海苔のみは 脂肪を増やす！
Seaweed alone increases fat!
ご飯もくま！ うぃーうぃーうぃーうぃー！
Eat rice too, wee wee wee wee!
やだ！ 気ませんね！ お仕置きマシーン！
No way! You're not listening! Punishment machine!
うっふんのプログラムは次こそ！
Next time, the sexy program for sure!
オーケー！ こよだよ！
Okay! It's Koyori!
研究室らしーい！ 新型！
Typical of a lab! A new model!
見逃しの新参！
A newcomer who missed it!
こよりの宿直は寝る！
Koyori's night shift is sleeping!
ヘルプ！
Help!
オールナイトニッポン！
All Night Nippon!
すももなんてね！ 見栄っ張り！
Plums or whatever! Show-off!
おもいいでスクウェア！
Memory Square!
オーケー！ こよだよ！
Okay! It's Koyori!
私の戦闘力は！ 54万です！
My combat power is 540,000!
下手くそは中卒です！
Clumsies are middle school graduates!
めんどくさい処置をお願いだよ！
Please do the troublesome treatment!
駆け抜けて！
Run through!
横顔好き！
I love your profile view!
やったー！ 間に合った！
Yay! Made it in time!
マヨネーズは飲み物です！
Mayonnaise is a drink!
鼻にフガチを吸う気で！
Breathing in fugachi through the nose!
お肉！ 全開！
Meat! Full throttle!
冷凍うどんわ常備してます？
Do you always keep frozen udon stocked?
どうですか？ はい！ やったー！
How is it? Yes! Yay!
証明完了！ QD！
Proof complete! QD!
コックだろコック！ にゃ！
You're a cook, right, a cook! Meow!
海苔のみは 脂肪を増やす！
Seaweed alone increases fat!
ご飯もくま！ うぃーうぃーうぃーうぃー！
Eat rice too, wee wee wee wee!
やだ！ 気ませんね！ お仕置きマシーン！
No way! You're not listening! Punishment machine!
うっふんのプログラムは次こそ！
Next time, the sexy program for sure!
オーケー！ こよだよ！
Okay! It's Koyori!
研究室らしーい！ 新型！
Typical of a lab! A new model!
見逃しの新参！
A newcomer who missed it!
こよりの宿直は寝る！
Koyori's night shift is sleeping!
ヘルプ！
Help!
オールナイトニッポン！
All Night Nippon!
すももなんてね！ 見栄っ張り！
Plums or whatever! Show-off!
おもいいでスクウェア！
Memory Square!
オーケー！ こよだよ！
Okay! It's Koyori!
私の戦闘力は！ 54万です！
My combat power is 540,000!
下手くそは中卒です！
Clumsies are middle school graduates!
めんどくさい処置をお願いだよ！
Please do the troublesome treatment!
駆け抜けて！
Run through!
横顔好き！
I love your profile view!
やったー！ 間に合った！
Yay! Made it in time!
マヨネーズは飲み物です！
Mayonnaise is a drink!
鼻にフガチを吸う気で！
Breathing in fugachi through the nose!
お肉！ 全開！
Meat! Full throttle!
冷凍うどんわ常備してます？
Do you always keep frozen udon stocked?
どうですか？ はい！ やったー！
How is it? Yes! Yay!
証明完了！ QD！
Proof complete! QD!
コックだろコック！ にゃ！
You're a cook, right, a cook! Meow!
海苔のみは 脂肪を増やす！
Seaweed alone increases fat!
へい！ カロスを照らす あの朝日のように
Hey! Like that morning sun illuminating Kalos,
（ニトロチャージ熱く行こうぜ）
(Let's heat things up with Nitro Charge!)
さあ！ 進もうぜ いつでも準備はオッケー
Now! Let's move forward, we're always ready!
（かたやぶりへんげい自在で）
(With Mold Breaker and Protean versatility!)
重なり合う想いがシンクロして
Our overlapping feelings synchronize,
決して消えない絆になるから
Forming an unbreakable bond,
どこまでも強くなれる 俺たちなら
So we can grow infinitely stronger, together!
(woah, woah, woah, yeah, yeah)
いくぜ！ 激しく燃えるバトル
Let's go! A fiercely burning battle,
いくぜ！ ピンチはチャンスだぜ
Let's go! A pinch is a chance!
いこうぜ！ きしかいせい
Let's go! With a miraculous comeback!
絶対に諦めない
We will never give up,
俺たちは諦めない
We will never give up!
へい！ 例えどんな壁が道を塞いだって
Hey! No matter what kind of wall blocks our path,
（いつでも当たって砕けろで）
(Always smash right through it!)
さあ！ この手で勝利の星を掴むんだ
Now! Grab the star of victory with your own hands!
（折れない不屈の心で）
(With an unbroken, indomitable heart!)
俺たちはいつでもどんな時も
No matter when or where,
同じ心で繋がってるから
We are always connected by the same heart,
何度でも立ち上がるぜ お前となら
So we can rise up again and again, as long as I'm with you!
いくぜ！ 手強いライバルたち
Let's go! Tough rivals ahead,
いくぜ！ 決めろ一撃必殺
Let's go! Land a one-hit KO!
いこうぜ！ 負けられない
Let's go! We cannot lose,
想いがここにあるから
Because our feelings are right here,
夢が俺にはあるから、yeah
Because I have a dream, yeah!
いくぜ！ 勝ちも負ける痛みも
Let's go! Sharing both victory and defeat,
いくぜ！ なんでも分け合える
Let's go! Sharing everything together,
いこうぜ！ 仲間がいる
Let's go! Our friends are here,
俺たちは一人じゃない
We are never alone!
いくぜ！ 激しく燃えるバトル
Let's go! A fiercely burning battle,
いくぜ！ ピンチはチャンスだぜ
Let's go! A pinch is a chance!
いこうぜ！ きしかいせい
Let's go! With a miraculous comeback!
絶対に諦めない
We will never give up!
いくぜ！ 譲れない夢がある
Let's go! There is a dream I won't surrender,
いくぜ！ 必ずゲットだぜ
Let's go! We'll definitely catch it!
いこうぜ！ 手を伸ばして
Let's go! Reach out your hand,
いつか描いた未来へ 誰も知らない高みへ、yeah
Toward the future we once imagined, to heights unknown, yeah!
さあ！ 上げてくぜ（100万ボルト）
Now! Let's turn it up (1 million volts)!
そう！ 立たみ向かって共に行こうぜ 見たことのない夢の向こうまで
Yes! Let's face it together and go beyond dreams ever seen!
へい！ 例えどんな壁が道を塞いだって
Hey! No matter what kind of wall blocks our path,
（いつでも当たって砕けろで）
(Always smash right through it!)
さあ！ この手で勝利の星を掴むんだ
Now! Grab the star of victory with your own hands!
（折れない不屈の心で）
(With an unbroken, indomitable heart!)
俺たちはいつでもどんな時も
No matter when or where,
同じ心で繋がってるから
We are always connected by the same heart,
何度でも立ち上がるぜ お前となら
So we can rise up again and again, as long as I'm with you!
いくぜ！ 手強いライバルたち
Let's go! Tough rivals ahead,
いくぜ！ 決めろ一撃必殺
Let's go! Land a one-hit KO!
いこうぜ！ 負けられない
Let's go! We cannot lose,
想いがここにあるから
Because our feelings are right here,
夢が俺にはあるから、yeah
Because I have a dream, yeah!
いくぜ！ 勝ちも負ける痛みも
Let's go! Sharing both victory and defeat,
いくぜ！ なんでも分け合える
Let's go! Sharing everything together,
いこうぜ！ 仲間がいる
Let's go! Our friends are here,
俺たちは一人じゃない
We are never alone!
いくぜ！ 激しく燃えるバトル
Let's go! A fiercely burning battle,
いくぜ！ ピンチはチャンスだぜ
Let's go! A pinch is a chance!
いこうぜ！ きしかいせい
Let's go! With a miraculous comeback!
絶対に諦めない
We will never give up!
いくぜ！ 譲れない夢がある
Let's go! There is a dream I won't surrender,
いくぜ！ 必ずゲットだぜ
Let's go! We'll definitely catch it!
いこうぜ！ 手を伸ばして
Let's go! Reach out your hand,
いつか描いた未来へ 誰も知らない高みへ、yeah
Toward the future we once imagined, to heights unknown, yeah!
いくぜ！ 激しく燃えるバトル
Let's go! A fiercely burning battle,
いくぜ！ ピンチはチャンスだぜ
Let's go! A pinch is a chance!
いこうぜ！ きしかいせい
Let's go! With a miraculous comeback!
絶対に諦めない
We will never give up!
いくぜ！ 譲れない夢がある
Let's go! There is a dream I won't surrender,
いくぜ！ 必ずゲットだぜ
Let's go! We'll definitely catch it!
いこうぜ！ 手を伸ばして
Let's go! Reach out your hand,
いつか描いた未来へ 誰も知らない高みへ、yeah
Toward the future we once imagined, to heights unknown, yeah!
いくぜ！ 譲れない夢がある
Let's go! There is a dream I won't surrender,
いくぜ！ 必ずゲットだぜ
Let's go! We'll definitely catch it!
いこうぜ！ 手を伸ばして
Let's go! Reach out your hand,
いつか描いた未来へ 誰も知らない高みへ、yeah
Toward the future we once imagined, to heights unknown, yeah!
誰も知らないてかみへ、yeah
To a handwritten letter nobody knows, yeah!
さあ！ あげてくぜ（逆転ボルト）
Now! Let's turn it up (Reversal Volt)!
そう！ 立ち向かって共に行こうぜ 見たことのない夢の向こうまで
Yes! Let's face it together and go beyond dreams ever seen!
ほらライブも来て！ ホロクスの頭脳！ 博衣こよりだよー！
Look, you came to the live too! Holox's brain, Hakui Koyori!
改めて今日は博衣こより生誕ライブ2026にお越しいただきありがとうございます！
Thank you once again for coming to Hakui Koyori's Birthday Live 2026 today!
コメントもいっぱいありがとう！ こよりよ見えてるよ、ありがとうー！
Thank you so much for all the comments too! Koyori sees you all, thank you!
ということで、ライブの感想やスクショはハッシュタグ #博衣こより生誕ライブ2026 をつけてたくさんポストしてください！
So please post your impressions and screenshots of the live using the hashtag #HakuiKoyoriBirthdayLive2026!
ねぇ、目指せ！超連動によろしくねぇ！
Hey, aim for it! Let's get fully synchronized!
はい。
Yep.
ということで、息が整ってないですけど、
So, I'm still catching my breath, but
さて、今年の生誕ライブ、テーマは、ゲームソングライブです！
now, for this year's birthday live, the theme is a Game Song Live!
これまでたくさんやってきた実況配信で、一緒に遊んできた思い出のゲームや、
We've packed in so many nostalgic games we played together in past game streams,
こよが大好きなゲーム関連の楽曲をたくさん詰め込みました！
and game-related songs Koyo loves!
最後まで全力で楽しんでいってね！
Enjoy it to the absolute fullest until the very end!
ということで、1曲目は大好きなポケモンのXYZを歌わせていただきました！ねぇ！
So, for the first song, we had you sing Pokémon's XYZ! Right?
じゅしくん！
Josh-kun!
はーい！俺はこの子と旅に出るっていうことです。
Right here! That means I'm going on a journey with this little guy.
はい、Xでセトリ予想もね、みんなにたくさんしてもらってたんですけど、
Yeah, everyone made tons of setlist predictions on X, but
ポケモンの予想は結構多かったけど、XYZを当てられた人は少なかったです。当たったきみ、おめでとう！
there were quite a few Pokémon predictions, but very few people guessed XYZ. Congratulations if you got it right!
ま、この曲は、Z-aに発売になったっていうのもあるんですけど、歌詞がめっちゃ良くて、実はこよにもぴったりな曲なので選びました！
Well, this song was also released around Z-a, but the lyrics are amazing, and it fits Koyo so well, so I chose it!
さあ、この後も自分の予想が当たってるかなってドキドキしながら楽しんでいってください！
Now, please enjoy the rest while wondering if your predictions were correct with excitement!
3Dを披露もあるからね、絶対に最後まで見てってね！
There's also 3D performances, so be sure to watch until the very end!
それでは、そろそろ次の曲！ゲームの世界へ、どうぞ！
Now then, almost time for the next song! Welcome to the world of games!
エアーマンが倒せない
I can't defeat Airman
気付いたら同じ面ばかりプレイ
Before I knew it, I was playing the same stage over and over,
そしていつも同じ場所で死ぬ
and always dying in the exact same spot.
あきらめずに消える足場に挑戦するけれど
Never giving up, I challenge the disappearing platforms,
すぐに下に落ちるよ
but I immediately fall below.
アイテム2号があれば 楽に向こうの岸まで着くけれど
If I had Item #2, I could easily reach the other side, but
何回やっても 何回やっても
no matter how many times I try, no matter how many times I try,
エアーマンが倒せないよ
I just can't defeat Airman!
あの竜巻 何回やっても避けない
No matter how many times I try, I can't avoid that tornado.
後ろに回って 撃ち続けても
Even if I get behind him and keep firing,
いずれは風に飛ばされる
I eventually get blown away by the wind.
タイム連打も ためしてみたけど
I tried using the time-barrage trick too,
竜巻相手じゃ 意味がない!
but against the tornado, it's useless!
だから次は絶対勝つために
So next time, for absolute victory,
僕はE缶だけは最後までとっておく
I'll save only the E-Tank until the very end.
気付いたらライフももう少ししかない
When I realize it, I only have a little bit of life left,
そしていつもそこでE缶つかう
and that's when I always use the E-Tank.
あきらめずにエアーマンまでたどり着くけれど
Never giving up, I manage to reach Airman,
すぐに残機なくなる
but I instantly lose my remaining lives.
リーフシールドがあれば 楽にエアーマンを倒せるけど
If I had the Leaf Shield, I could easily defeat Airman, but
何回やっても 何回やっても
no matter how many times I try, no matter how many times I try,
ウッドマンが倒せないよ
I just can't defeat Woodman!
落ちる木の葉は 何回やっても避けない
No matter how many times I try, I can't dodge the falling leaves.
後ろに下がって 距離をとっても
Even if I step back and keep my distance,
いずれは距離を詰められる
he eventually closes the distance.
タイム連打も ためしてみたけど
I tried using the time-barrage trick too,
あいつのジャンプはくぐれない
but I can't slip under his jump.
僕はE缶だけは最後までとっておく
I'll save only the E-Tank until the very end.
アイテム2号があれば 楽に向こうの岸まで着くけれど
If I had Item #2, I could easily reach the other side, but
何回やっても 何回やっても
no matter how many times I try, no matter how many times I try,
エアーマンが倒せないよ
I just can't defeat Airman!
あの竜巻 何回やっても避けない
No matter how many times I try, I can't avoid that tornado.
気付いたら 同じ面ばかりプレイ
I've noticed that every time I play around that same spot
そしていつも 同じ場所で死ぬ
that I always die at the same place.
あきらめずに 消える 足場に
Never giving up, I challenge
挑戦するけれど すぐ下に落ちるよ
the disappearing footholds, but soon fall below!
アイテム2号があれば 楽に向こうの岸までつけど
If I had item #2 I could easily reach the other side, but
何回やってても 何回やってても
no matter what, however many times I try...
エアーマンが倒せないよ
I cannot defeat Airman!
あの竜巻 何回やってても避けられない
No matter how many times I try, I cannot avoid that tornado!
後ろに回って 撃ち続けても いずれは風に飛ばされる
I get behind him and fire repeatedly, but the wind hurls me back.
タイム連打も ためしてみたけど 竜巻相手じゃ意味がない!
I tried the time barrage too, but against the tornado it's meaningless!
だから次は 絶対勝つために
Thus, for the sake of absolute victory
僕はE缶だけは最後までとっておく
I will only take the E-Tank at the very last moment.
気付いたら ライフももう少ししかない
When I notice I've only got a little bit of life left
そしていつも そこでもE缶つかう
that's when I always use the E-Tank.
あきらめずに エアーマンまでたどり着くけれど
Never giving up, I pursue the road to Airman
すぐに残機なくなる...
but soon I lose my remaining lives...
リーフシールドがあれば 楽に エアーマンを倒せるけど
If I had Leaf Shield, Wood Man would be a breeze to defeat, but
何回やってても 何回やってても
no matter what, however many times I try...
ウッドマンが倒せないよ
I cannot defeat Wood Man!
落ちる木の葉は 何回やってても避けられない
No matter how many times I try, I cannot dodge the falling leaves.
後ろに下がって 距離をとっても いずれは距離を詰められる
I step back for distance, but he always closes in.
タイム連打も ためしてみたけど あいつのジャンプはくぐれない!
I tried the time barrage too, but I cannot dodge his jump!
だから次は 絶対勝つために 僕はE缶だけは最後までとっておく
Thus, for absolute victory, I'll save the E-Tank till the very end.
あてもなく彷徨っていた 手がかりもなく探し続けた
Alone for a while I've been searching through the dark for traces of love...
あなたがくれた思い出を 心を癒す詩にして
To weave the memories you gave me into a healing song.
あなたが見せた微笑みを 心を癒す歌にして
Turning the smile you showed me into a song that heals the heart.
心を癒す歌にして
Into a song that heals the heart...
あてもなく さまよっていた
Without a destination, I was wandering
手がかりも さがしつづけた
Searching continuously for a clue,
あなたがくれた 思い出を
the memories you gave me
心をいやす 詩にして
turned into a song that heals the heart.
約束も することもなく
Without even making promises,
かわす言葉も 決めたりもせず
or deciding on words to exchange,
抱きしめ そしてたしかめた 日々は二度と帰らぬ
holding you close and confirming—those days will never return.
記憶の中の 手を振るあなたは
You, waving in my memories,
わたしの名を 呼ぶことが出来るの
can you still call my name?
あふれる その涙を
Changing those overflowing tears
輝く 勇気にかえて
into shining courage,
命は つづく 夜を越え
life continues across the night,
疑うことのない 明日へとつづく
continuing toward an unquestioned tomorrow.
飛ぶ鳥の 向こうの空へ
To the sky beyond the flying birds,
いくつかの記憶 預けたのだろう
you must have entrusted several memories there.
僅かな希望も 夢も
Even meager hopes and dreams
届かぬ場所に忘れて
forgotten in a place they cannot reach.
めぐり逢うのは 偶発と言えるの
Can our meeting be called a coincidence,
別れる時が 必ず来るのに
when the time to part will surely come?
消えてゆく運命でも
Even if it's a fading destiny,
君が生きている限り
as long as you are alive,
命はつづく 永遠に
life continues forever.
その力の限り どこまでも
With all its might, no matter where.
わたしが死のうとも
Even if I should die,
君が生きている限り
as long as you are alive,
命はつづく 永遠に
life continues forever.
その力の限り どこまでもつづく
With all its might, continuing no matter where.
私が死のうとも
Even if I should die,
君が生きている限り
as long as you are alive,
命はつづく 永遠に
life continues forever.
その力の限り どこまでもつづく
With all its might, continuing no matter where.
どこまでもつづく
Continuing no matter where.
きみの瞳に映る わたしは何色ですか
Reflected in your eyes, what color am I?
赤深き望むなら 渡そう陽の光を
If you want deep red, let's pass the light of the sun
藍深き望むなら 渡そう高き空を
If you want deep blue, let's pass the high sky
歓びが溢れ 巡りあいできました
It was full of joy, and we met once again
哀しみが溢れ 瞳閉じました
My sadness overflowed and my eyelids closed
こぼれた雫は 心に沁みゆく
The spilled drops linger in my heart
行き渡る波は 弱く交えます
The waves that go around are weak
とどけしゆりかご 眠りをさそう
Cradle, cradle, let's sleep
夢に懐かし 面影をさがす
I miss my dream, searching for familiar faces
手を伸ばし強く 抱きしめたくなる
I want to reach out and hold you tightly
届けしゆりかご 眠りをさそう
Cradle, cradle, let's sleep
夢に懐かし 面影をさがす
I miss my dream, searching for familiar faces
手を伸ばし強く 抱きしめたくなる
I want to reach out and hold you tightly
きみの瞳に映る わたしは何色ですか
Reflected in your eyes, what color am I?
緑深き望むなら 渡そうこの大地を
If you want deep green, let's pass this earth
きみの瞳に映る わたしは何色ですか
Reflected in your eyes, what color am I?
藍深き望むなら 渡そう高き空を
If you want deep blue, let's pass the high sky
歓びが溢れ 巡りあいできました
It was full of joy, and we met once again
こぼれた雫は 心に沁みゆく
The spilled drops linger in my heart
不安定な神様 繰り返す出会いと別れ
Unstable god, repeating meetings and partings
また会えるその日まで 時かける旅人
Until the day we can meet again, a traveler through time
あなたが泣いている 流れる涙の雨
You are crying, tears flowing like rain
泣くなとは言わない 心悲しくって
I won't say "don't cry", because my heart is sad
生きとし生きるもの 何かを背負いながら
Every living thing, while carrying something
見えない鎖に つながれている
Is bound by invisible chains
どれほど救われただろう
How many times have I been saved?
あどけない笑顔を 失いたくはない
I don't want to lose that innocent smile
不安定な神様 繰り返す過去と未来
Unstable god, repeating past and future
生まれ そして死んでいく運命
The destiny of being born and then dying
かけ違えた世界で 繰り返す出会いと別れ
In a world of misunderstandings, repeating meetings and partings
また会えるその日まで 時かける旅人
Until the day we can meet again, a traveler through time
淀みのない心 黒く染めゆきながら
While dyeing a pure heart black
抑えられなくて 解き放たれる
It cannot be suppressed and is unleashed
何回名前を呼んだだろう
How many times have I called your name?
あどけない笑顔は もうどこにもない
That innocent smile is nowhere to be found anymore
不安定な神様
Unstable god...
継いだ夢と愛を
Inherited dreams and love,
育て守り託しゆく運命
a fate to nurture, protect, and entrust.
掛け違えた世界で探すたび引き裂かれても
In a mismatched world, even if we're torn apart each time we search,
また会えると信じて時かける旅人
believing we'll meet again, the traveler leaps through time.
不安定な神様 繰り返す 過去と未来
Unstable god, a cycle of past and future,
けがれのない心 黒く染めゆくながら
A pure heart, as it's slowly tainted black,
抑えられなくて 解き放たれる
unable to be held back, is set free.
何回 名を呼んだだろう
How many times did I call your name?
あどけない笑顔は もうどこにもない
That innocent smile is nowhere to be found.
不安定な神様 引き継いだ 夢と愛を
Unstable god, dreams and love inherited,
育て 守り 託しゆく運命
a fate to nurture, protect, and entrust.
掛け違えた世界で 探すたび引き裂かれても
In a mismatched world, even if we're torn apart each time we search,
また会えると 信じて 時かける旅人
believing we'll meet again, the traveler leaps through time.
不安定な神様 繰り返す 過去と未来
Unstable god, a cycle of past and future,
生れて そして 死んでいく運命
a fate of being born then dying.
掛け違えた世界で 繰り返す 出会いや別れ
In a mismatched world, a cycle of meetings and farewells,
また会えるその日まで 時かける旅人
until the day we meet again, the traveler leaps through time.
Until the day we meet again, the traveler leaps through time.
また会えるその日まで 時かける旅人
はいということで、すわらさんにお越しいただき一緒に歌わせていただきました！
So, we invited Suara-san to join us and sing together!
すわらさん、自己紹介をいただいてもよろしいでしょうか？
Suara-san, could you please introduce yourself?
はい、Suaraです。
Yes, I'm Suara.
「うたわれるもの」シリーズの主題歌をたくさん歌っているものです。
I sing many theme songs for the "Utawarerumono" series.
はい、ようこそ！
Yes, welcome!
こよりさん、ありがとうございます！
Koyori-san, thank you very much!
そうなんです、実はですね、「うたわれるもの」というゲーム、昨年約3ヶ月間かけてシリーズの3部作を実況プレイさせていただいたんですけれど、
That's right, actually, last year I spent about three months doing a Let's Play of the trilogy of the "Utawarerumono" games,
その「うたわれるもの」、本当に曲がめちゃくちゃいいのですが、その歌をほぼ全てSuaraさんが歌っていらっしゃるというのデス。
and the songs in "Utawarerumono" are just incredible, and almost all of those songs are sung by Suara-san,
のデス。
y'know!
はい、もう耳が今日本当に幸せで。
Yes, my ears are truly blessed today.
いやこちらこそです、本当に。
No, the feeling is mutual, truly.
もう何というか、恐縮な恐れを多い状態なんですけれども、ありがとうございます！
I'm in a state of awe and humility, but thank you so much!
ありがとうございます、本当に。
Thank you very much, truly.
そう、Suaraさんには実は4周年の時に逆凸でメッセージも頂戴しておりまして、
Actually, Suara-san sent me a surprise voice message during my 4th anniversary,
その時にいつか一緒に歌いたいというのもこよりも結構熱烈なラブコールをさせていただいていたんですけれども、その思いを本日叶えることができました！
and I gave a pretty passionate love call saying I wanted to sing together someday, and today that wish finally came true!
あの、ちょっと質問が何個かあるんですけれど、
Um, I have a few questions,
実はあの「うたわれるもの」の実況をしていた時に、最終回でSuaraさんがコメントをして下さいまして、
actually, when I was doing the Let's Play of "Utawarerumono", Suara-san left a comment on the final episode,
はい、あのこよりの実況をちょっとご覧くださったと思うんですけど、
yes, and I think you watched a bit of Koyori's Let's Play,
あの見られますか、実況とかって普段？
do you usually watch Let's Plays or anything like that?
いや、ちょっと実はですね、初めてあの見させていただいて、
Well, actually, this was the first time I got to watch one,
そうなんですか？
is that right?
そうなん、あの、まあ、えっと、アクアプラスのね、スタッフの方とかも、「あの子よりさんってね、うたわれ配信してるよ」って言って、あの情報は聞いていたんですよ。
Yes, I heard from the Aqua Plus staff and others that "Koyori-san is streaming Utawarerumono," so I had heard about it.
で、私のライブに来てくれるファンのの方たちからも、「あの聞いてたんです、ぜひ見てみてください」って言って。
And fans of mine who come to my live shows also told me, "I heard about it, please go check it out."
それで、あの、見させていただいたっていうのが、あの、最終回だったんですけれども。
So that's how I ended up watching it, starting with the final episode.
そうだったんですね！恐縮です、なんか。
Is that so! I'm so honored, somehow.
いやもう、すごい、あの、本当に、こう、こよりさんのうたわれるものへの愛がすごい溢れてて、本当に見てて、もう最後までずっとあの、見させていただいて。
But it was amazing, really, Koyori-san's love for Utawarerumono overflowed so much, and watching it all the way to the very end,
で、あ、コメントを送りたいな、でももう早くしないと終わっちゃうって思いながら。
thinking, "I want to send a comment, but I need to hurry or it'll end,"
で、あの同じ部屋に、あの私の息子がいたんですけど、
and in the same room, my son was there,
で、息子に、あのコメントちょっと送ってみてもいいと思う？って言って、
and I asked him, "Do you think it's okay if I send a comment?" and he said,
聞いたら、あの「いんちゃう？」って言って、
"Why not?"
いい息子さんだ！
What a great son!
それでലുംもう本当に震える手でコメント打って、もう、あ、早くもうエンターキーをこう、
And I typed the comment with trembling hands, thinking, "Hurry up and hit the Enter key,"
そんな緊張してくださってたんですか？
were you that nervous?
遅そ、遅そ、どうしよう、でも早押すな、みたいな。
"It's late, it's late, what should I do, but don't rush," sort of thing.
はい それでもう ドキドキしながら
Yes, and while my heart was pounding,
あのー おくらせていただいたり
I got to send messages to you...
すーさんね あのー コメント気づいてくださって もうっ
Suara-san, you noticed my comments, and I was...
とっても嬉しかったです
just so, so happy!
こよりもですし 見てた女子くんたちもものすごく もう 嬉しくってやっぱり あの 見ていただけるっていうのが
Me, and all the viewers watching too—we were so happy that you actually watch us!
うたわれるさんとか 赤プラスさんもそうですし その公式の皆様にご覧いただけるって本当に嬉しくって恐縮なことなので
Whether it's Utawarerumono or Aquaplus, having the official staff watch us is truly an honor and so wonderful.
もう 幸せでございました ありがとうございました
I was so happy. Thank you very much.
すごい楽しくて見いっちゃいました 本当に もうすごい長時間ね されてるのがすごいなと思って 本当に はい
It was so much fun, I got completely hooked. I think it's amazing that you stream for such long hours, really.
ね その日の夜も歌枠も聞かせていただいたり すごい体力だなと思いながら
And, you know, I listened to your singing stream that night too, thinking you have incredible stamina.
楽しんでるのね 歌われるものが本当に素晴らしい作品だったからですのですね ですので その歌われるものともずっと付き合っていらっしゃる はい すーさんですけれども
Because Utawarerumono is such a wonderful work to enjoy! And Suara-san, you've been involved with it for so long—
推しキャラとかっていらっしゃるんですか
do you have a favorite character?
推しキャラですか 推しキャラはやっぱりちょっと エルルゥっていうことに あの
A favorite character? Well, my favorite is... Eruruu, you could say—
ってことにしと おかないとね ちょっとフォークで刺されるかもしれない
You have to say Eruruu! Otherwise, you might get stabbed with a fork.
あ あれもしやもしかして あの 中が良い そのね
Oh, wait, could it be because you have a good relationship with, you know...
中の方のね 柚木涼香さんとね とっても仲良くさせていただいてて 本当になんか アニメの 放送の時からですね あの 2006年からずっと仲良くさせていただいて
with Yuzuki Ryoka-san, the voice actress? We've been super close ever since the anime broadcast back in 2006, and...
20年 そうですね 20年 すごい
20 years! / That's right, 20 years!
はい もうそれはエルルゥ推し はい ですね と いうこともあって もうエルルゥ推し ということでお願いします
So that's why you're an Eruruu fan! With that in mind, Eruruu fan it is!
これはもうあの アルルゥが大好きなので エルルゥアルルゥで 姉妹で 姉妹で 嬉しいです
Well, since I love Aruruu too, Eruruu and Aruruu—as sisters! As sisters! I'm so happy.
嬉しいです はい ということで もっともっとお話したいんですけれどもう時間が来てしまいまして もう本当に今日は一緒に歌っていただきありがとうございます
I'm so happy. Well, with that, I'd love to talk more, but our time is up. Thank you so much for singing with me today.
ありがとうございます 小夜里さんの本当に柔らかい 優しいね 温かい声にこう包まれながら 私も一緒にね 歌えて本当に 幸せでした
Thank you. Being wrapped in Koyori-san's truly soft, gentle, and warm voice, and singing together with you, I was truly happy.
恐縮でございます
I am deeply honored.
またぜひ いろいろご一緒させていただける機会があれば嬉しいです ぜひぜひよろしくお願いします
I'd be so happy if we have more opportunities to perform together. / Please, absolutely, looking forward to it.
ありがとうございます と いうことで スアラさんでした ありがとうございます
Thank you very much. So that was Suara-san! Thank you so much!
やがて女はきれいになるだろう
Before long, women will grow beautiful,
マッチでアイス マッチ大好き 大好き 大好き
Match ice? Match I love you, love you, love you,
ポトスのように媚びて生きる人生
Living life fawningly like a pothos plant,
本当の自分に出ない よっしゃ
Unable to be your true self... Yay!
あのねダンスがセクシーな女なんなの
Hey, what's with women whose dancing is so sexy?
めちゃしてきでーままですてきよー
Super stylish, mama so wonderful!
輝きたい 愛されたい 輝きたい 愛されたい
I want to shine, I want to be loved, I want to shine, I want to be loved,
歴史がほって置かない よっしゃ
History won't leave you alone, yay!
離れない感じで インキタイン
Inseparable feeling—ink it in!
あー 悲しい歌が流れる あー 胸の中歩く
Ah, a sad song plays. Ah, walking in my heart.
波風が流れちゃう 波風が流れちゃう
Letting the waves flow by, letting the waves flow by...
どうしてなんだろ よっしゃ
Why is that? Yay!
ワン ツー スリー で わんだほー ワン ツー スリー で わんだほー
One, two, three and wonderful! One, two, three and wonderful!
ピカピカに破り捨てて 誰も信じられなくちゃ
Tearing it up shiny and new, if nobody can be trusted,
いいだけ泣きたいだけ泣かなきゃいい
I just want to cry, if you don't cry, it's fine.
ワン ツー スリー で わんだほー ワン ツー スリー で わんだほー
One, two, three and wonderful! One, two, three and wonderful!
だから全く一緒して 胸の中すぎってめまいがみえなくなっても
So, being totally together, even if dizziness inside your chest makes you unable to see,
できちゃうんだもん だいすき 大好き 大好き 大好き
Because you can do it! Love you, love you, love you, love you!
こっち見て マジだいすき 大好き 大好き 大好き
Look over here! Seriously love you, love you, love you, love you!
みっつん
Mittsun!
愛♡スクリーム！
Ai♡Scream!
アイスクリーム
Ice cream!
教えて もっと あなたのこと
Tell me more about you.
Tell me もももも Tell me もももも
Tell me mo-mo-mo-more, Tell me mo-mo-mo-more!
聞かせて もっと あなたの声
Let me hear more of your voice.
Let me hear もももも Let me hear もももも
Let me hear mo-mo-mo-more, Let me hear mo-mo-mo-more!
こんなドキドキ もう最近出ない
I can't feel this kind of heartbeat lately.
Oh! I need you, Oh! I need you
友達は卒業 運命の私に
I've graduated from being friends, find me,
見つけて 欲しいの
your destined girl!
勇気を 出して
Gather your courage,
見つめる 作戦
The staring strategy!
手と手が 触れれば
When our hands touch,
もう 止められない
I can't stop anymore!
止められない
Can't stop it!
や!や!や!や! この恋 この愛で
Yay, yay, yay, yay! With this love and affection,
ベンベン！ティーとけちゃうよ（ちゃうよ）
Melt, melt! The tea is melting away!
ねえねえねえ 気付いてマイダリン
Hey, hey, hey, notice me, my darling,
届けて 大好き！
and deliver my deepest love!
アイスクリーム アイスクリーム 叫びましょう
Ice cream, ice cream, let's shout it out!
アイスクリーム アイスクリーム
Ice cream, ice cream!
こよりちゃん！
Koyori-chan!
はーい！何が好き？ 迷わず よりもお前が！
Yes! What do you like? More than anything, you!
あずきちゃん！
AZKi-chan!
はーい！何が好き？ こしあん つぶあん よりも あなた！
Yes! What do you like? Smooth paste, chunky paste, more than anything, you!
ラミィちゃん！
Lamy-chan!
はーい！何が好き？ お酒よりも あなた！
Yes! What do you like? More than alcohol, you!
みんな！はーい！何が好き？ もちろん 大好き こづみ！
Everyone! Yes! What do you like? Of course, I love kuzumochi!
止められない
Can't stop it!
や!や!や!や! この恋 この愛で
Yay, yay, yay, yay! With this love and affection,
ベンベン！ティーとけちゃうよ（ちゃうよ）
Melt, melt! The tea is melting away!
ねえねえねえ 気付いてマイダリン
Hey, hey, hey, notice me, my darling,
届けて 大好き！
and deliver my deepest love!
アイスクリーム アイスクリーム 叫びましょう
Ice cream, ice cream, let's shout it out!
アイスクリーム アイスクリーム
Ice cream, ice cream!
お願い 見つけてマイダリン
Please find me, my darling!
お願い 気付いてマイダリン
Please notice me, my darling!
勇気を 出して
Gather your courage,
近づく 作戦
The approaching strategy!
手と手が 触れれば
When our hands touch,
もう 止められない
I can't stop anymore!
や!や!や!や! この恋 この愛で
Yay, yay, yay, yay! With this love and affection,
ベンベン！ティーとけちゃうよ（ちゃうよ）
Melt, melt! The tea is melting away!
ねえねえねえ 気付いてマイダリン
Hey, hey, hey, notice me, my darling,
それは あなた！
That's you!
アイスクリーム アイスクリーム 叫びましょう
Ice cream, ice cream, let's shout it out!
アイスクリーム アイスクリーム
Ice cream, ice cream!
アイスクリーム アイスクリーム 叫びましょう
Ice cream, ice cream, let's shout it out!
アイスクリーム アイスクリーム
Ice cream, ice cream!
ララララ...
Lalala...
こみ上げてくる涙を 何回拭いいたら
How many times do I have to wipe away the tears that well up?
伝えたい言葉は 届くだろう?
Will the words I want to convey ever reach you?
誰かに何か怒っても 出口はないなら
If there is no exit even if you get angry at someone,
何度でも 何度でも 何度でも 立ち上がり呼ぶよ
I will stand up again and again and again and call your name
きみの名前
call your name
声が枯れるまで
until my voice becomes hoarse.
悔しくて苦しくて がんばってもどうしようもない時も
Even when I'm frustrated, painful, and struggling with nowhere to turn,
きみを思い出すよ
I remember you.
10000回だめでも
Even if 10,000 times end in failure
へとへとになっても
and I'm exhausted,
10001回目は
the 10,001st time
何か変わるかもしれない
just might change something.
口にする度 本当に伝えたい言葉は ぽろぽろこぼれて 逃げていく
Every time I speak, the words I truly want to convey spill out and run away.
悲しみに支配されて 壊されそうになるなら
If I'm dominated by sadness and about to be crushed,
何度でも 何度でも 何度でも 立ち上がり呼ぶよ
I will stand up again and again and again and call your name
きみの名前 声が枯れるまで
until my voice becomes hoarse.
落ち込んでやる気も もう底ついていて
Even when I'm depressed, my motivation has hit rock bottom,
がんばれない時も
and I can't do my best,
きみを思い出すよ
I remember you.
10000回だめでも
Even if 10,000 times fail
かっこ悪くても
and I look uncool,
10001回目は
the 10,001st time
何か変わるかもしれない
just might change something.
前を向いてしがみついて胸襟むしってあきらめないで叫べ!
Facing forward, clinging on, scratching at my chest, don't give up, shout!
何度でも 何度でも 何度でも 立ち上がり呼ぶよ
Again and again and again, I will stand up and call
きみの名前 声が枯れるまで
your name until my voice is hoarse.
この先も躓いて 傷ついて傷つけて
Even from now on, stumbling, getting hurt, hurting others,
終わりない やり場のない 怒りさえもどかしく
holding onto endless, aimless anger with frustration,
抱えながら どうしてわからないんだ? 伝わらないんだ?
why don't I understand? Why won't it convey?
喘ぎ嘆きながら 自分と戦ってみるよ
While gasping and sighing, I'll try to fight with myself.
10000回だめでも 望みなくなっても
Even if 10,000 times fail and I have no hope left,
10001回目は 来る
the 10,001st time will come.
きみを呼ぶ声 力にしていくよ
I'll make the voice that calls you my strength.
何度も 明日はその10001回目かもしれない
Again and again, tomorrow might be that 10,001st time.
落ち込んでやる気も もう底ついていて
Even when I'm depressed, my motivation has hit rock bottom,
がんばれない時も
and I can't do my best,
きみを思い出すよ
I remember you.
10000回だめでも
Even if 10,000 times fail
かっこ悪くても
and I look uncool,
10001回目は
the 10,001st time
何か変わるかもしれない
just might change something.
前を向いてしがみついて胸襟むしってあきらめないで叫べ!
Facing forward, clinging on, scratching at my chest, don't give up, shout!
何度でも 何度でも 何度でも 立ち上がり呼ぶよ
Again and again and again, I will stand up and call
きみの名前 声が枯れるまで
your name until my voice is hoarse.
暗闇に誓い 惜しくも敗れて 報われないワンフレーズ
Sworn in the darkness, narrowly defeated, a futile one-phrase
いつもここに 流れていた 遠い未来へ祈るよ
always flowed right here, praying toward a distant future.
忘れられない あの日々の声も 追いかけて 追いかけて
Chasing and chasing the unforgettable voice of those days,
滑り込んだ この想い
this feeling slipped right in.
青い空に ふとあふれてた
Suddenly overflowing into the blue sky,
遠く遠く
far, far away.
追いかけて 追いかけて 滑り込んだ この想い
Chasing and chasing, this feeling slipped right in,
青い空に ふとあふれてた 遠く遠く
suddenly overflowing into the blue sky, far, far away.
遠く遠く
Far, far away.
目覚めては繰り返す 眠い朝は
Waking up to a repeating sleepy morning,
襟のタイをきつく締め
I fasten my necktie tightly.
教室のドアくぐるとうほんの少し
I walk through the classroom door and can stick out my chest
胸を張って歩き出せる
ever so slightly as I step forward.
そんな日常に 吹き抜ける風
The wind blowing right through such ordinary days
聞いた気がした
I felt like I heard.
感じた気がしたんだ
I felt like I sensed it
震え出す今この胸で
right here in my trembling heart,
もう来る気がした
feeling like it would come again.
幾億の星が消えていくのを 見送った 手を振った よかったね、と
I saw off hundreds of millions of vanishing stars and waved goodbye.
廊下の隅見下ろす 掃除の途中
While cleaning, I looked down into the corner of the corridor,
おかしいものだと思う 頭の中の時は止まってるのに
thinking how strange it is, even though the time inside my head has stopped,
違う日々を生きてるように
living through different days.
塵は雪のように降り積もる
Dust piles up like snow.
待ってる気がした
I felt like it was waiting,
呼んでる気がしたんだ
felt like it was calling to me.
震え出す今この時が
This trembling moment right now
見つけた気がした
I felt like I had found it.
失われた記憶が呼び覚ました 物語 永遠のその終わり
The memories I lost awakened an eternal story at its end.
いつの間にか駆けだしていた あなたに手を引かれてた
Before I knew it, I was running, pulled along by your hand.
手を振った
...hands.
よかったね、と
I'm glad, aren't I?
廊下の隅見下ろす掃除の途中
Looking down the hallway while cleaning,
おかしなものだと思う
I find it all rather strange.
あたしの中の時は止まっているのに
Even though time inside me has stopped,
違う日々を生きてるように
it's like I'm living completely different days.
埃は雪のように降り積もる
Dust piles up just like snow.
待ってる気がした
I felt like I was waiting,
呼んでる気がしたんだ
I felt like someone was calling out.
震え出す今この時が
Right now, my trembling heart...
見つけた気がした 失われた記憶が呼び覚ました
...felt like it had found lost memories.
物語
A story...
永遠の
of eternity...
その終わり
that's coming to an end.
いつの間にか駆け出してた あなたに手を引かれてた
Before I knew it, I was running out, pulled by your hand.
昨日は遠く 明日はすぐ
Yesterday felt so far, but tomorrow is right here.
そんな当たり前に心が踊った
My heart leaped at something so simple.
聞こえた気がした
I felt like I heard it,
感じた気がしたんだ
I felt it.
震え出す今この胸で
Now this trembling soul...
もう来る気がした
...felt like it was about to happen.
幾千の朝を越え 新しい日が
Crossing thousands of mornings, a new day...
待ってる気がした
felt like it was waiting,
呼んでる気がしたんだ
felt like it was calling.
震えてるこの魂が
This trembling soul...
見つけた気がした
felt like it had finally found it.
幾億の夢のように消え去る日を
Just like fading away into thousands of dreams,
見送った
I looked back.
手を振った
I waved my hand...
ありがとう、と
and said, "Thank you."
ぽつり灯り管制塔
A lone beacon stands atop the control tower,
砂嵐の向こうへ 祈るように綴った
looking out beyond the sandstorm, as if praying.
管制塔より
From the Control Tower...
作詞・作曲・編曲：堀江晶太
Lyrics, Composition, Arrangement: Oki Junta
ラジオネーム 匿名希望
Radio Name: Anonymous Hope
お便り届いてますか
Are my messages reaching you?
この世界がいつからか
This world, at some point,
まるで他人事のように やけに静かなので
became so quietly distant,
不安になったのです
that it made me feel uneasy,
思い出したのです
and made me remember it all.
人知れず口を濁んだまま 終われないのです
Just rambling on and on, unable to stop—
それは嫌なのです
I hated that it had to be this way.
夢ってもっと わがままだったでしょう
I wish I could dream a little more selfishly.
忘れてよ 笑ってよ 気付いてよ
Forget it, laugh it off, realize it—
此処に居るのにさ 意地悪だな
since I'm stuck right here being so spiteful.
誰にも届かない光を どうしたら伝えられるのでしょう
How am I supposed to convey a light that reaches no one?
どうしても伝えたいよ
No matter what, I want to convey it to you.
ラジオネーム　匿名希望
Radio name: Anonymous
育児はしないのだろうか
Will childcare not be done?
それとも向こうの世界には　僕は邪魔なのだろうか
Or perhaps in the world beyond, am I in the way?
だとしても綴るよ　微塵もなく捨てるよ
Even so, I'll write it out, throwing away every bit of doubt
振られたって好きだよ　いいでしょう
Even if I'm rejected, I love you. That's fine, right?
いいでしょう
That's fine, right?
楽しかったよね　悔しかったよね
It was fun, wasn't it? It was frustrating, wasn't it?
もう独り言は嫌だ
I'm sick of talking to myself anymore.
「待たせちゃったかな」　「別に待ってないよ」
"Did I make you wait?" "I wasn't really waiting."
夢と呼んだそれも僕だっただけ　もういいかい
Even what I called a dream was just me all along. Are you ready?
応えてよ　笑ってよ　気付いてよ
Answer me, smile, notice me!
此処に居るのにさ　意地悪だな
Even though I'm right here, you're so mean.
誰にも届かない光を　僕たちは光と呼び続ける
The light that reaches no one, we keep calling "light".
真夜中　管制塔から　あなたを明かしてやる
From the control tower in the dead of night, I'll reveal you to the world!
応えてよ　笑ってよ　気付いてよ
Answer me, smile, notice me!
此処に居るのにさ　意地悪だな
Even though I'm right here, you're so mean.
誰にも届かない光を
The light that reaches no one...
どうして変えられないのだろう
Why can't I change it?
どうしても伝えたいよ
No matter what, I want to convey it.
ということで、新曲のお披露目、フルアニメーションMV公開の告知、新3Dのお披露目を、全部どどんとまとめて、やらせていただきました！
And with that, we've made all the announcements at once!
情報量多かったけど、追いついてるかな？
That was a lot of information, are you keeping up?
はい、ちょっとね、新3Dが可愛すぎて気になっちゃうと、思うんですけど、まずは、おり曲の話からさせてください！
I know the new 3D is so cute that you might get distracted, but first, let's talk about the original song!
お披露目させていただいたのは、新曲「管制塔より」！
The one we revealed is the new song "Kanseitou yori"!
ついに、あの、堀江晶太さんに書き下ろしていただきました！みんな、どうだったー？
Finally, commissioned from Shota Horie-san! Everyone, how was it?
え、もういい、よかったー！
Oh, it was so good!
はい、そしてですね、いまちょっと映像も流してすぐお引合いてくれててめっちゃ嬉しいんですけど、このライブ終了直後にフルアニメーションMVがプレミア公開されます！
And right after this live ends, the full animation MV will premiere!
たぶんもう、あの、まねちゃんがポチッてしてくれてると思うんですけど、世界観がめちゃくちゃこだわられている映像作品になっているので、何回も見て、聴いて、そしてちょっと世界観の考察とかしてみてください！
Since it's a video with incredible detail in its worldview, please watch, listen, and ponder it!
え、そして、お待たせしました！ちょっと待って、一個言い忘れました。えっと、さっきのね曲、管制塔より24時にリリースもあります！よろしくお願いします！
And the release for that song "Kanseitou yori" is also at midnight! Please look forward to it!
え、そしてですね、お待たせしました！新3D！どう？かわいい？かわいい？かわいい！
And now, thank you for waiting! The new 3D! How is it? Cute? Cute? Cute!
はい、もっとね話すことなく見せたいんだけど、ちょっとね、ももこまわの、あの、あれ、いつものにすごい近くなったんじゃないかなと思います！
I want to show you even more, but it's become super close to my usual Momoko Mama style!
え、この後のメイン限ライブでね、撮影会もしまして、さらに細かく見せちゃうので、ぜひメイン限ライブも来てください！
In the limited main live, we'll have a photo session to show you even more, so please come!
メイン限ライブでは、本篇で歌えなかった、あのゲームの、みんなが大好きな曲、「きんきんきんきん」も歌うよ！お楽しみに！
At the limited main live, I'll also sing everyone's favorite game song, "Kinkin"! Look forward to it!
じゃあ、一つだけ新3Dのめちゃ変わったポイントを教えちゃうと…ケモ耳が揺れます！おー！かわいい！はい！
Now, let me share just one really unique point... My animal ears sway! Ohh! Cute! Yes!
ってことでね、
So with that, being...
ええ、
Yeah.
あ、あとトレンド1チーム本当にありがとうございます！
Oh, and Trend 1 Team, thank you so much!
今日急だったじゃないですか、むっちゃ嬉しかったし、
Today was pretty sudden, but I was so happy...
トレンド3さんなんかすごいいっぱい入ってたみたいで、
and Trend 3 seemed to have a lot of entries too.
本当にありがとー！
Thank you so much!
さあはもう一つ大事なお知らせです。ドン！
And now, one more important announcement. Bam!
博衣こより誕生日記念グッズ2026が発売されます！やー！
Hakui Koyori's Birthday Commemorative Goods 2026 are now on sale! Yay!
早速詳細を見ていきましょう。
Let's go straight into the details.
まず1つ目はちら、え、もふこにもなる！2Wayブランケット。
First up is this 2-Way Blanket that can turn into Mofuko!
お部屋でゲームを楽しんでいるこよりのかきおろしイラストです！
It features Koyori's raw illustration of her enjoying games in her room!
イラストはもっちろんママこ！
The illustration is, of course, by Mama-Mofuko!
これ丸めるともふこように早変わりして、持ち運びも楽ちんだしそのまま飾っても可愛いですね！
If you roll it up, it quickly turns into Mofuko, making it super easy to carry around and cute to display!
続いてはちら、
Next is this:
ボイスキーホルダー ～ゲーム実況編～
Voice Keychain ~Game Let's Play Edition~
待望のボイスキーホルダーが出ました！こよりの取り下ろしボイスが入っているもので、
Long-awaited voice keychains featuring Koyori's unreleased voice lines have arrived!
今回はライブに合わせてゲーム実況っぽいセリフ、絶叫が6種類入っております！セリフはこよが考えましたー！イラストはなもり先生です。
This time, it features six types of game-let's-play-style rants and catchphrases tailored for the live, all thought up by Koyori herself! The illustration is by Namori-sensei.
続いてはちら、こより監督ぬいぐるみスマホスタンド！
Next is this: Koyori Director Plush Smartphone Stand!
あのこより監督がついにぬいぐるみになったよ！かわいい！
Director Koyori has finally turned into a plushie! So cute!
そのまま飾るもよし、スマホスタンドにもなるので超便利です！絶対ゲットしてね！
You can display it as-is, and it also doubles as a smartphone stand, so it's super convenient. You've gotta get one!
最後はちら、
And finally, this:
ゲーム風カードホルダー！
Retro Game-Style Card Holder!
特典のチェキ風ブロマイドとかホロカモ入れられて、持ち運べちゃうカードホルダーです。
It comes with a cheki-style bromide and can hold a Holocame too, making it a card holder that's easy to carry around!
中に入っている台紙のイラストはこよちゃんが描き下ろした！
The illustration on the insert was drawn by Koyori herself!
ゲーム風のデザインもレトロゲームっぽくて可愛くない？
The retro game design is also super cute!
はい、そしてフルセット特典はこちらです。
And the Full Set special bonus is right here:
ももこママ描き下ろしのチェキ風ブロマイドが付きます。
A cheki-style bromide featuring Mama-Mofuko's illustration!
数量限定版は直筆サインと箔押し箔押し複製メッセージ入りチェキ風ブロマイド、通常版は直筆サインの複製繊維とメッセージ入りになってます。
The quantity-limited version includes a handwritten signature, a foil-stamped handwritten message, and the bromide, while the regular version includes a printed replica of the handwritten signature and message with the bromide.
販売開始がこのあと21時10分にあるので、皆さんあの慌てないで大丈夫です！10分からなので！はい、あの見てって下さい！よろしくお願いします！
Sales start at 21:10 today, so everyone, don't panic, it's okay, it starts in 10 minutes, so please take a look! Thank you!
さらに特典ASMRボイスも付きます！毎年恒例の、君の誕生日を逆に祝っちゃうASMRボイス2026版。こちらですね、毎年みんな誕生日まで我慢して聞いて「わあ！」ってなっているのですごく嬉しく思ってます。ぜひゲットしてください！
Furthermore, a special ASMR voice is also included, featuring Koyori celebrating your birthday in reverse, something everyone waits for every year just to endure until their birthday and scream "Yay!" Be sure to get it!
ということで、ええ、ととのおしらせでしたが、かわいいでしょ？
So, that wraps up the announcements! Cute, right?
みんながかわいいって言ってくれてて、こよ嬉しいよ！表情とかもちょっと変わったんですよ。にゃーん。
Everyone keeps saying it's cute, and Koyori is so happy. My expressions and stuff changed a bit too! Nyan!
あ、これができない顔になりました。
And this "Can't do it" face!
あとは、き！いえーい！こんな表情もできるようになりました。配信を楽しみに！
And "Yay!" Yeah, I can make this expression now too, so look forward to the stream!
ということで今日は博衣こより生誕ライブ2026ゲームソングライブに見に来てくれて、ありがとー！
So today, thank you so much for coming to watch the Hakui Koyori Birthday Live 2026 Game Song Live!
このあとですね、新曲のアニメMV公開と麺ゲンライブ、あですね、ええ、アニメMV公開見て、で10分かな、グッズ買って、15分からメンゲンライブって感じで、ゆっくり順番にいけるようになっているので、あわてず、かけず、なんだろ、さず？笑でよろしくお願いします！
And after this, we have the new anime MV release and the MenGen Live, so with the anime MV release first, then 10 minutes to buy merch, and then 15 minutes for the MenGen Live, everything is scheduled nicely in order so don't rush, don't panic, and don't push it, haha, please look forward to it!
ということで、今日はちょっと遅れちゃったんだけど、この3Dお披露目して、生誕ライブもできて、大好きなゲームソングいっぱいお披露目できて、嬉しかったよみんな本当に見に来てくれて、ありがとー！
So today, I was a bit late, but I was able to unveil the 3D model, hold the birthday live, and share all my favorite game songs with everyone. I'm so glad everyone came to see it! Thank you so much!
また会おうね！ありがとー！MV見てねー！
See you again! Thank you! Watch the MV, okay?
ぽつり 灯り 管制塔
A solitary light flickers on the control tower.
砂嵐 の 向こう へ
Reaching out into the sandstorm,
祈る よう に 縋っ た
as if praying for the days to come.
これ から の こと
ラジオネーム 匿名 希望
Radio name: Anonymous, hope you're doing well.
お便り 届い て い ます か
Are my messages reaching you?
この 世界 が いつ から か
Ever since when, it feels like this world
まるで 他人事 の よう に
has become like someone else's affair.
やけに 静か な ので
It's so unusually quiet,
不安 に なっ た の です
which is why I grew uneasy,
思い出し た の です
and then I remembered.
人知れず 口 を 噤ん だ まま
With my mouth secretly sealed,
終わり されない の です
it's still not over.
それは 嫌 な の です
And I hate that.
夢 って もっと わがまま だっ た でしょ う
Maybe dreams are just a bit too selfish.
応え て よ 、 笑っ て よ 、 気付い て よ
Answer me, smile, notice me!